在之前的阅读中，我们讨论了快照图，
In a previous reading, we talked about snapshot diagrams,
这些是系统内部事物的图片。
which are these pictures of how things look inside the system.
当我们谈到这一点时，我们的区别之一
And when we talked about that, one of the distinctions we made
有些对象是不可变的。
is that some objects are immutable.
一旦它们被创造出来，它们总是
Once they're created, they always
表示相同的值。
represent the same value.
其他对象是可变的。
And other objects are mutable.
可变对象的方法
Mutable objects have methods that
让您更改该对象的值。
let you change the value of that object.
例如，String是不可变类型的一个示例。
String, for instance, is an example of an immutable type.
StringObject始终表示同一字符串。
StringObject always represents the same string.
StringBuilder是一种可变类型。
StringBuilder is a mutable type.
它有删除部分字符串的方法，
It has methods that delete parts of the string,
或插入或替换字符，或附加
or insert or replace characters, or append
人物等等。
characters, and so forth.
既然字符串是不可变的，一旦它被创建，
So since String is immutable, once it's created,
它总是有同样的价值。
it always has the same value.
为了在结尾添加一些东西
In order to add something to the end
一根绳子，你到底在做什么
of a string, what you're actually doing
正在创建新字符串。
is creating a new string.
所以当你说s加等于b或者s等于s加b，
So when you say s plus equals b or s equals s plus b,
实际上——在内部，Java只是调用一个方法
these actually-- internally, Java simply calls a method
concat（）在那个字符串上。
concat() on that string.
但这实际上并没有改变原始的string对象。
But that doesn't actually change the original string object.
相反，它创建了一个新的字符串对象。
Instead, it creates a new string object.
我们必须重新分配一个变量，就像s，
And we have to reassign a variable that we had, like s,
指向新字符串对象的点。
the point to that new string object.
相反，StringBuilder对象是可变的。
In contrast, StringBuilder objects are mutable.
StringBuilder有直接
StringBuilder has methods that directly
更改对象的值。
change the value of the object.
因此，StringBuilder上的append（）是非常不同的
So in particular, append() on a StringBuilder is very different
而不是字符串上的concat（），因为它实际上在变异
than concat() on a string because it's actually mutating
对象。
the object.
它不会返回新的字符串。
It's not returning a fresh string.
这意味着，特别是，我们没有
That means, in particular, we don't have
重新分配这个sb变量。
to reassign this sb variable.
它继续指向同一个物体，
It continues to point to the same object,
但那个物体的意思是，那个物体的价值已经改变了。
but that object meaning, that object's value has changed.
那又怎么样？
So what?
在这两种情况下，你最后都会提到
In both cases you end up with s or sb referring
到字符串ab。
to the string of characters ab.
坦率地说，可变对象和不可变对象之间的区别
Frankly, the difference between mutable and immutable objects
什么时候有都不重要
doesn't matter much when there is
在这些情况下，只有一个对象的引用。
only one reference to an object like there is in these cases.
但是在如何
But there are big differences in how
当有多个引用时，它们的行为
they behave when there are multiple references
到目标。
to the object.
例如，如果我们分配一个字符串变量
So, for example, if we assign a string variable
指向现在这个新对象
t to point to now this new object that s
现在s和t指向字符串ab。
is pointing to so that s and t now point to the string ab.
同样，我们将tb指定给同一个对象
And similarly, we assign tb to point to the same object
某人所指的行为
that sb is pointing to, then the behavior
在每个对象上附加一个字符
of appending a character to each of those objects
完全不同。
is very different.
在此处更改t将创建新字符串。
Changing t here creates a fresh string.
所以它对s的意思没有影响。
And so it has no effect on what s means.
s仍然指向字符串ab。
s still points to a string ab.
但是使用tb变量附加一个字符
But appending a character using the tb variable
更改该对象值。
changes that object value.
所以某人也看到了同样的变化。
So sb sees the same change.
这就是问题的本质
And that's the essence of the problem
我们将在这篇文章中看到。
that we're going to look at in this reading.
因为这对程序员来说是非常令人惊讶的
Because this can be very surprising to programmers
可能是虫子的来源。
and can be a source of bugs.
现在，我们可能会问，既然我们有这个不可变的字符串类，
Now, we might ask, since we have this immutable String class,
为什么我们甚至需要一个可变的StringBuilder？
why do we even need a mutable StringBuilder?
好吧，它的一个常见用法是连接一个大数
Well, a common use for it is to concatenate a large number
弦在一起。
of strings together.
所以如果我们只是用弦，
So if we were just using strings,
这就是我们要编写的代码。
this is the kind of code we would write.
每次连接的运行结束时间
Running end times made concatenating each time
我们要加的数字n。
the number n that we're adding.
但是不可变字符串的问题
But the problem with immutable strings
这是很多临时拷贝。
is that this makes lots of temporary copies.
当然，第一个数字实际上被复制了n次，
The first number is actually copied n times in, of course,
最后一根绳子。
building up the final string.
它实际上花费了二次方时间
It actually costs quadratic time just
做所有的复制，即使我们只是连接
to do all that copying, even though we only concatenated
最后是n个元素。
n elements in the end.
所以StringBuilder的设计目的是最小化它的复制。
So StringBuilder is designed to minimize its copying.
它有一个简单但聪明的内部数据
It's got a simple but clever internal data
一种完全避免复制的结构。
structure that avoids doing any copying at all.
它只保存字符串列表
It simply keeps a list of strings
直到你要最后一根弦的时候
until the very end when you ask for a final string
有两个字符串的列。
with a two-string column.
事实上，取得好成绩
In fact, getting good performance
是我们
is one of the main reasons why we even
首先使用不可变对象。
use immutable objects in the first place.
另一个是，分享可以很方便。
Another is that the sharing can be convenient.
有时你想要你的程序的两部分
Sometimes you want two parts of your program
能够通过分享彼此交流
to be able to communicate with each other by sharing
一种常见的可变数据结构。
a common mutable data structure.
今天的阅读是关于这个的危险
Today's reading though is about the dangers of this
让你知道你得到了什么
so that you know what you're getting
当您选择使用不可变对象时。
into when you're choosing to use immutable objects.